STEVEN PELTZER

Los Angeles, CA | 559-804-0529 | stevenrpeltzer@gmail.com | stevenpeltzer.com | github.com/srpeltz | linkedin.com/in/steven-peltzer

SUMMARY

I am a web developer that has recently graduated from General Assembly's Web Development Immersive course. During my time at General Assembly I was taught multiple frameworks such as MEAN stack and Ruby on Rails, which has enabled me to work proficiently as a full stack web developer. Having my roots beginning with farming and my first steps in my career in music I have come to find that tech is my passion and the next step I want to take in my career. I believe that my past experience and musical skill is very transferable by knowing the characteristics of patience and hard laborious work. I am currently working on my Recipe Collective web app and implementing the Ionic framework to make it suitable for mobile app stores.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery | MongoDB | Express | Angular | Node | SQL | PostgreSQL | Ruby on Rails | Github | Bootstrap

PROJECTS - ONE WEEK AGILE SPRINTS

Recipe Collective - MongoDB | NodeJS | Express | Angular | JWTs - I intentionally created this website to get familiar with consuming third party API's. Coordinating with a classmate, I was able to display recipes on my site that he created on his. Doing this and using JavaScript Web Tokens for authentications, this project was a valuable experience for me.

Gossip Hollywood - Ruby | Rails | PostgreSQL - I made this app for all the assistants in the entertainment industry that need to voice their woes. Other users can read, vote, and comment on how outlandish they think the story is.

Virtual Town Hall - MongoDB | Express | NodeJS | EJS | Passport - This app is for the use your local representatives and constituents. By moving the polling process from the town hall to online, you remove any need for cancelling a town hall or voicing your opinion. You can make a post as a representative to present your proposal and voice your opinion as a voter.

Ball is Life - JavaScript | jQuery | Canvas - A simple game where the player must jump over the obstacles that come towards them. In order to accomplish this I had to teach myself to use Canvas after only taking the course for two weeks.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

ZipRecruiter.com Annual Hackathon - 1st Place in MVP Category

• "Binnacle" is a web app to help active job seekers stay organized. Built with **React** and **Foundation** in 32 hours

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Stealth Venture Labs - Front-end Web Developer (freelance) | El Segundo, CA

May 2017- Present

- Did client facing website re-design for Tuner Crate using HTML, CSS, ¡Query in Shopify Liquid
- Communicated with designers and project manager to receive mockups and clarify details and developer limitations
- Developed mobile view and desktop view
- Gave constructive criticism on conventional coding practices after working in a pre-existing project

BLT Communications - Department Coordinator | Hollywood, CA

Nov 2015-Jan 2017

- Organized billing payments and accounting documents for 25+ high profile clients
- Created and maintained heavily relied on accounting documents to help company executives make informed decisions on distributing workload, responsibilities, and determining if the company was profitable.
- Implemented company policy and procedure for a department with 50+ employees for smooth functionality
- Managed day-to-day schedules for the departments 3 upper level executives

WORKS Entertainment - Day-to-day Manager / Artist Manager Assistant | Beverly Hills, CA

Feb 2014-Oct 2015

- Handled day-to-day management duties for clients A Great Big World, Morgan James, and Boh Doran by scheduling
 entire tour runs and promo trips. Coordinated with venues, promoters, tour managers, bus/car rentals, equipment
 rentals, traveling logistics and more.
- Offices designated PRO (Performing Rights Organization) and publishing administrator
- Involved in creative environments for coming up with music video ideas and marketing campaigns for album releases and video releases
- Only assistant to two managers with nine clients, I was in charge of office organization and maintaining all artist documents and online properties

Television Music Services NBC Universal - Music Promo Coordinator (Temp) | Universal City, CA June 2013-Feb 2014

- Created quote and license requests and researched song splits for music clearance
- Responsible for training new hires duties and proper procedure expected of NBC
- · Handled large volume of requests, licenses, and payments
- Generated quarterly PRO (Performing Rights Organization) reports

EDUCATION

California State University, Northridge – BA in Music Industry Studies General Assembly - Web Development Immersive course completion certificate